movieinsider.com 2019-05-02

# Feedback - About Us - Privacy Policy - Movie Insider

#### About Movie Insider®

**Movie Insider offers behind-the-scenes film information about upcoming Hollywood and independent releases. Movies are tracked and updated through all stages of film production from concept/announcement, development, production, post-production and finally to release.

Since 1999, Movie Insider has strived to provide the up-to-date upcoming movie releases dates based on confirmed third-party announcements, applicable major and independent distributors and other reporting. 

**

Movie Insider is owned and operated by The Movie Insider LLC. 

##### History of the Site

Movie Insider was first launched on free webhost _AOL Hometown_ in July 1999 by its founder Brian D. Renner (age 13 at the time!) who had a strong passion in movies and computers. Back then, the mission of the Movie Insider website was "to keep you and everyone else up to date about the world of movies". Not long after the initial launch, Brian moved the website to _Yahoo! Geocities_ and some other free hosts, followed by its first domain name "movie-insider.com" (registered by a third-party, because Brian's mom was afraid to use a credit card online!) in July 2000. Soon after a third-party ownership issue regarding this first domain name, Brian purchased "themovieinsider.com" (his mom finally relented to letting him use her credit card!) and re-launched his website again under "themovieinsider.com" on September 10, 2000. Since 2000, the Movie Insider website has gone through numerous changes/pivots, recreations and redesigns. Many are available for review by using the **Internet Archive's WayBack Machine**. 

With an [**October 2010 domain arbitration case**](http://domains.adrforum.com/domains/decisions/1345100.htm), Brian was granted "movieinsider.com" from a recognized domain squatter (who had picked it up in August 2000 between the registration of "movie-insider.com" [July 2000] and "themovieinsider.com" [September 2000]) and eventually moved the Movie Insider website from "themovieinsider.com" to "movieinsider.com". In 2012, Brian finally secured "movie-insider.com" again too! 

##### Movie Insider Team 

#####  Brian D. Renner  
Founder and Managing Member, Movie Insider LLC

As Founder and Managing Member of Movie Insider LLC, Brian handles the site's strategy development, day-to-day editorial direction, advertising demand and partnership relations, and oversees contracted editorial contributors and programmers. 

From 2009 to 2011, Brian worked as the Digital Marketing Manager at the Detroit field office of Allied Global Marketing, an entertainment promotion/publicity agency, where he crafted digital proposals and campaigns for various Hollywood studios. Prior to Allied, Brian interned with the Worldwide Post-Production Planning team at Walt Disney Pictures where he assisted in the management of animated and live-action post-production timelines for theatrical and home entertainment releases. 

Brian was honored as one of ["Twenty in their 20's"](http://www.crainsdetroit.com/files/twenty07/20_renner.html) by _Crain's Detroit Business_ in May 2007, and featured on [CBS Radio/CBSLocal.com](http://detroit.cbslocal.com/2013/12/04/passion-for-movies-leads-to-entrepreneurial-success-online/) in December 2013. 

  * New Movie Trailers
  * New Movie Photos
  * Movie Feed & Updates

#### Newsletter

The free weekly Movie Insider email newsletter about this week's movie releases.

#### Subscribe to the Newsletter

#### Unsubscribe from Newsletter

#### Advertising

If you are interested in advertising on Movie Insider, please contact us.

**__Email Address:** [advertising@movieinsider.com](mailto:advertising@movieinsider.com)  
**__Phone:** (248) 387-9826

#### Terms of Service & DMCA Guidelines

### Servicemarks

Movie Insider® is a registered servicemark of The Movie Insider LLC. 

"Taking You Beyond The Studio Gates", the distinctive Movie Insider logo and other custom graphics are servicemarks and/or trade dress of The Movie Insider LLC.

### Request to Modify or Remove Content

Movie Insider strives to provide information at every stage of a movie, from concept to release, fulfilling our motto to take you beyond the studio gates. We continually search for accurate and reliable information from a wide variety of sources. Most updates link to the original source of the information.

If you believe that there is inaccurate, infringing or unauthorized content on Movie Insider, contact us using the email form on this page. Please include the URL(s) of the information in question. We will promptly review the applicable request and determine the appropriate actions. If you do not believe our response to be adequate, you can send a Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA)-compliant notification to our designated agent:

**__Designated Agent:** The Movie Insider LLC  
**__Mailing Address:** The Movie Insider LLC, P.O. Box 1626, Birmingham, Michigan 48012-1626   
**__Email Address:** [dmca@movieinsider.com](mailto:dmca@movieinsider.com)  
**__Phone:** (248) 387-9826

### Copyrighted Material

Copyrights and trademarks for films mentioned on Movie Insider are held by their respective owners and are used with permission or fall under fair use exceptions. Any inquiries related to the use of the content of the films mentioned on this website should be directed to the applicable studio, distributor and/or production company.

### Re-Use of Material

Movie Insider contains a combination of public and copyrighted material. In general, you can re-use content from Movie Insider under the fair use exemptions or similar provisions of copyright law. You should provide attribution by including a hyperlink back to the Movie Insider page on which the material is located and, if applicable, the original source cited. However, regardless of citations, improper uses may violate copyrights including those of third parties.

### No Warranties on Service or Content

Movie Insider reserves the right to add, edit or discontinue the transmission of our services and content provided on our website. You understand and agree that this website is provided **"AS-IS"** with no responsibility for the accurateness, timeliness, quality, deletion, mis-delivery or failure of our services and content.

Under no circumstances will Movie Insider be liable in anyway for any content, including, but not limited to, for any errors or omissions in any content, or for any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of the use of any content posted, emailed or otherwise transmitted via our website.

### Harm to Your Computer

**You understand and agree that the use, access and/or download of information through Movie Insider website is at your own discretion and risk.** You will be solely responsible for any damage to your property and any loss of data that results from the use of our website.

#### Privacy and Cookies Policy

The Movie Insider LLC ("us", "we", or "our") operates the movieinsider.com website (the "Service"). Our registered address is: The Movie Insider LLC, P.O. Box 1626, Birmingham, Michigan 48012-1626. 

This Privacy Policy informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. 

If you live within the European Union, per the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you can learn your rights and our obligations to you in regards to the processing and control of your personal data by reviewing the information provided at [**knowyourprivacyrights.org**](http://www.knowyourprivacyrights.org/).

##### Definitons

##### Personal Data

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

##### Usage Data

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

##### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User's device (see also our Cookie Policy). Some cookies may last for a defined period of time, such as one day or until you close your browser. Others last indefinitely.

##### Data Controller

Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.

##### Data Processor (or Service Providers)

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

##### Data Subject

Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

##### User

The User (or "you") is the individual using our Service. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

* * *

###  Consent to Information Collection and Use

We aim to obtain your consent to process information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you. 

Under GDPR, the legal basis of our Service is to process information based on your consent, cf. GDPR art. 6(1)(a), and you may at any time withdraw your consent (see "Tracking & Cookies Data"). 

##### Types of Data Collected

#### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Cookie IDs 

Such Personal Data may be collected when you contact us for support and/or subscribe to our newsletter. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track activity and show/display advertisements on our Service.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, IDs, and scripts to collect and track information and to show/display advertisements on our Service.

When you first visit our Service (e.g. desktop, mobile, etc.), **we may ask you whether you wish us to use cookies**. If you choose not to accept them, we shall not use them for your visit except to record that you have not consented to their use for any other purpose. You can also instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. 

The type of cookies we use:

  * **Storage and access of information:** The storage of information, or access to information that is already stored, on your device (such as advertising identifiers and/or other device identifiers).
  *  **Personalization:** The collection and processing of information to subsequently personalize advertising for you (based on user interests). 
  * **Ad selection, reporting and delivery:** To select and deliver advertisements and to measure the delivery and effectiveness of such advertisements. This includes using previously collected information about your interests to select ads, processing data about what advertisements were shown, how often they were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether any action related to the advertisement, including for example clicking an ad or making a purchase on a third-party website.
  *  **Content delivery, selection and reporting:** To select and deliver content and to measure the delivery and effectiveness of such content. 
  * **Measurement:** To measure, understand, and report on user usage of content (such as the number of pageviews per page). 

##### Use of Data

The Movie Insider LLC uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

##### Retention of Data

The Movie Insider LLC will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

The Movie Insider LLC will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

##### Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. Our Service is currently hosted on a secured web server in a data center located in the United States. Applicable server backups are also located in the United States. 

If you are located outside United States, specifically in the European Union, and choose to provide information to us, please note that the data is processed in the United States.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

The Movie Insider LLC will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

##### Disclosure Of Data

##### Business Transaction

If The Movie Insider LLC is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

##### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, The Movie Insider LLC may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

##### Legal Requirements

The Movie Insider LLC may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of The Movie Insider LLC
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

##### Security and Encryption of Data

The security of your data is important to us. Our Service uses a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificate throughout to verify our identity to your browser and to encrypt any data you give us. We maintain appropriate technical, security and organisational measures to protect Personal Data against unauthorized or unlawful processing and use, and against accidental loss, destruction, damage, theft or disclosure. 

##### "Do Not Track" Signals

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

##### Your Rights

The Movie Insider LLC aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us. You likely will need your anonymous, random and encrypted key, saved in the first party cookie for our Service. 

In certain circumstances, you have the right:

  * To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you
  * To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
  * To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

##### Service Providers

We may employ third-party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

##### Analytics

We use Google Anlytics, a third-party Service Provider, to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en). The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms page: [**google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/**](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

##### Advertising

We use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.

These Service Providers include Google AdSense & DoubleClick. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: **[google.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/)**.

##### Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

##### Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

##### Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

##### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

**__Email Address:** terms@movieinsider.com  
**__Phone:** (248) 387-9826  
**__Mailing Address:** The Movie Insider LLC, P.O. Box 1626, Birmingham, Michigan 48012-1626

#### Cookie Policy

The Movie Insider LLC ("us", "we", or "our") uses cookies on the movieinsider.com website (the "Service").

Our Cookies Policy explains what cookies are, how we use cookies, how third-parties we may partner with may use cookies on the Service, your choices regarding cookies and further information about cookies.

##### What are cookies

Cookies are small pieces of text sent to your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Service or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Service more useful to you.

Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your personal computer or mobile device when you go offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

##### How The Movie Insider LLC uses cookies

When you use and access the Service, we ask you whether you wish us to use cookies. If you choose not to accept them, we shall not use them for your visit except to record that you have not consented to their use for any other purpose. 

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * To enable certain functions of the Service

  * To provide analytics

  * To enable advertisements delivery

We use both session and persistent cookies on the Service and we use different types of cookies to run the Service:

  * Operational cookies. We may use our necessary cookies to handle basic functions, including page navigation, track star ratings and preferences (no authentication).

  * Analytics cookies. We may use analytics cookies to track information how the Service is used so that we can make improvements. We may also use analytics cookies to test new advertisements, pages, features or new functionality of the Service to see how our users react to them.

  * Advertising cookies. These type of cookies are used to deliver advertisements on and through the Service and track the performance of these advertisements. These cookies may also be used to enable third-party advertising networks to deliver ads that may be relevant to you based upon your activities or interests.

##### Third-party cookies

In addition to our own cookies, we may also use various third-parties cookies to report usage statistics of the Service, deliver advertisements on and through the Service, and so on.

##### What are your choices regarding cookies

If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser.

Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly.

  * For the Chrome web browser, please visit this page from Google: **[support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050)**.

  * For the Internet Explorer web browser, please visit this page from Microsoft: **[support.microsoft.com/kb/278835](https://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835)**.

  * For the Firefox web browser, please visit this page from Mozilla: **[support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored)**.

  * For the Safari web browser, please visit this page from Apple: **[support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US)**.

  * For any other web browser, please visit your browser's official web pages.

##### Where can you find more information about cookies

You can learn more about cookies and the following third-party websites:

  * AllAboutCookies: [**allaboutcookies.org**](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

  * Network Advertising Initiative: [**networkadvertising.org**](https://www.networkadvertising.org/)

__**Last Updated:** May 14, 2018
